<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Ronan Paugam</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-07-04T11:15:49-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ronan Paugam</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Deforestation Fire in Brazil</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2011/09/01/brazil/"/>
   <updated>2011-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/09/01/brazil</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jbkjY3p12mc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a collaboration with Saulo Freitas from INPE on a FAPESP grant, I intended a prescribed fire in Acre, Brazil in September 2011.This burnt was organized on the experimental site of EMBRAPA in Rio Branco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video shows synchronized visible (left) and Middle Infra Red (MIR; right) cameras operated from a helicopter hovering above the plot. The helicopter was courteously provided by the police department of Acre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video is accelerated 4 times. The acquisition rate of the MIR camera was 0.33Hz while the visible operated at 25Hz. This difference explains the time-lapse effect on the temperature map.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Heather Fire Northumberland</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2010/03/01/northumberland/"/>
   <updated>2010-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/03/01/northumberland</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/data/northumberland/northumberland_overView.png&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Northumberland Overview&quot;&gt;
This page shows data of a 945 m² prescribed fire conducted in Northumberland (UK) in March 2010 (Dold et al., 2010). The NERC Airborne Research and Survey Facility (ARSF) participated to this experiment, collecting, amongst other datasets, high resolution (39 megapixel) Leica RCD105 digital frame camera imagery during a series of overpasses. One Leica image is shown above, and was compared with thermal imageries collected from a handheld IR imager (AGEMA 550) operated in flown from the helicopter located on the bottom left corner of the image. The IR imageries were used to derived maps of brightness temperature and fire radiative power (FRP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The burn plot was a rectangle of  45 m by 21 m. The vegetation was a homogeneus fuel bed made of heather, with a density of 1.5 +/- 0.5 kg/m² and a moisture content of 60 +/- 2%. The fire was ignited simultaneously on the northern edge as a back fire line, and at the south east corner as an ignition point. During the  fire, the helicopter was hovering around 120 m above ground, and was observing the plot with view azimuth and zenith angles of around 8 and 55 degree, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animations below shows the raw thermal brightness temperature time-series, as captured by the handheld AGEMA 550 camera in the helicopter (left), along with the corresponding geo-referenced imagery from which metrics like fire front rate of spread can be derived (right) (see paugam et al 2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Some Pictures from the Ground:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/data/northumberland/flame-front-propagation_800x400.png&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Northumberland fire: flame front&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/data/northumberland/ignition-with-drip-torche800x400.png&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Northumberland fire: Drip Torche Ignition&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
